{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "The number of integer solutions of the equation 2|x|(x^2 + 1) = 5x^2 is:",
        "answer": "3"
      },
      {
        "question": "The equation x^3 + (2r + 1)x^2 + (4r − 1)x + 2 = 0 has −2 as one of the roots. If the other two roots are real, then the minimum possible non-negative integer value of r is:",
        "answer": "2"
      },
      {
        "question": "Let α and β be the two distinct roots of the equation 2x^2 − 6x + k = 0, such that (α+β) and αβ are the distinct roots of the equation x^2+px+p = 0. Then, the value of 8(k−p) is:",
        "answer": "6"
      },
      {
        "question": "Anil invests Rs. 22000 for 6 years in a certain scheme with 4% interest per annum, compounded half-yearly. Sunil invests in the same scheme for 5 years, and then reinvests the entire amount received at the end of 5 years for one year at 10% simple interest. If the amounts received by both at the end of 6 years are the same, then the initial investment made by Sunil, in rupees, is:",
        "answer": "20808"
      },
      {
        "question": "The amount of job that Amal, Sunil, and Kamal can individually do in a day are in harmonic progression. Kamal takes twice as much time as Amal to do the same amount of job. If Amal and Sunil work for 4 days and 9 days, respectively, Kamal needs to work for 16 days to finish the remaining job. Then the number of days Sunil will take to finish the job working alone is:",
        "answer": "27"
      },
      {
        "question": "Arvind travels from town A to town B, and Surbhi from town B to town A, both starting at the same time along the same route. After meeting each other, Arvind takes 6 hours to reach town B while Surbhi takes 24 hours to reach town A. If Arvind travelled at a speed of 54 km/h, then the distance, in km, between town A and town B is:",
        "answer": "972 km"
      },
      {
        "question": "In a right-angled triangle △ABC, the altitude AB is 5 cm, and the base BC is 12 cm. P and Q are two points on BC such that the areas of △ABP, △ABQ, and △ABC are in arithmetic progression. If the area of △ABC is 1.5 times the area of △ABP, what is the length of PQ, in cm?",
        "answer": "4 cm"
      },
      {
        "question": "A lab experiment measures the number of organisms at 8 am every day. Starting with 2 organisms on the first day, the number of organisms on any day is equal to 3 more than twice the number on the previous day. If the number of organisms on the nth day exceeds one million, then the lowest possible value of n is:",
        "answer": "19"
      },
      {
        "question": "A visa processing office (VPO) accepts visa applications in four categories – US, UK, Schengen, and Others. The applications are scheduled for processing in twenty 15-minute slots starting at 9:00 am and ending at 2:00 pm. Ten applications are scheduled in each slot. There are ten counters in the office, four dedicated to US applications, and two each for UK applications, Schengen applications and Others applications. Applicants are called in for processing sequentially on a first-come-first-served basis whenever a counter gets freed for their category. The processing time for an application is the same within each category. But it may vary across the categories. Each US and UK application requires 10 minutes of processing time. Depending on the number of applications in a category and time required to process an application for that category, it is possible that an applicant for a slot may be processed later. On a particular day, Ira, Vijay and Nandini were scheduled for Schengen visa processing in that order. They had a 9:15 am slot but entered the VPO at 9:20 am. When they entered the office, exactly six out of the ten counters were either processing applications, or had finished processing one and ready to start processing the next. Mahira and Osman were scheduled in the 9:30 am slot on that day for visa processing in the Others category. The following additional information is known about that day: 1. All slots were full. 2. The number of US applications was the same in all the slots. The same was true for the other three categories. 3. 50% of the applications were US applications. 4. All applicants except Ira, Vijay and Nandini arrived on time. 5. Vijay was called to a counter at 9:25 am. How many UK applications were scheduled on that day?",
        
        "answer": "0"
      },
      {
        "question": "A visa processing office (VPO) accepts visa applications in four categories – US, UK, Schengen, and Others. The applications are scheduled for processing in twenty 15-minute slots starting at 9:00 am and ending at 2:00 pm. Ten applications are scheduled in each slot. There are ten counters in the office, four dedicated to US applications, and two each for UK applications, Schengen applications and Others applications. Applicants are called in for processing sequentially on a first-come-first-served basis whenever a counter gets freed for their category. The processing time for an application is the same within each category. But it may vary across the categories. Each US and UK application requires 10 minutes of processing time. Depending on the number of applications in a category and time required to process an application for that category, it is possible that an applicant for a slot may be processed later. On a particular day, Ira, Vijay and Nandini were scheduled for Schengen visa processing in that order. They had a 9:15 am slot but entered the VPO at 9:20 am. When they entered the office, exactly six out of the ten counters were either processing applications, or had finished processing one and ready to start processing the next. Mahira and Osman were scheduled in the 9:30 am slot on that day for visa processing in the Others category. The following additional information is known about that day: 1. All slots were full. 2. The number of US applications was the same in all the slots. The same was true for the other three categories. 3. 50% of the applications were US applications. 4. All applicants except Ira, Vijay and Nandini arrived on time. 5. Vijay was called to a counter at 9:25 am. What is the maximum possible value of the total time (in minutes, nearest to its integer value) required to process all applications in the Others category on that day?",
        
        "answer": "200"
      }
    ]
  }
  